http://www.kadantjohnson.com/privacy-statement

In-line filters can have
a single or duplex arrangement. A single in-line filter is used in applications where the flow can be interrupted, or the filter can be bypassed when the filter element is serviced. Duo filters are used when continuous filtration is required.
Learn More
M-clean™ System
The M-clean system is a modular cleaning system for fabrics, belts, and rolls in process industries.
Learn More
Press Section Felt Cleaning Assembly
Among other applications, the press section felt cleaning assembly, also known as UHLE pipe, is designed to enhance uniform CD dewatering and cleaning, and minimize energy consumption on the press section of a paper machine.
Learn More
Doctor & Roll Cleaning Blades
Doctor and roll cleaning blades are used to clean rolls and remove stock accumulations, water, pitch, and filler buildup.
Learn More
Doctor & Roll Cleaning Blade Holders
Proper doctoring or roll cleaning is critical to many industrial processes and goes beyond choosing a doctor or roll cleaning blade.
Learn More
Roll Cleaner Assemblies
Roll cleaner assemblies are comprised of a roll cleaning blade, blade holder, structural beam, brackets and bearings along with an option to oscillate.
Learn More
Fluid Handling
Desuperheaters
Desuperheaters reduce the temperature of superheated steam to its saturation point for optimal heat transfer and efficiency.
Learn More
Direct Steam Injection Heaters
A direct steam injection heater provides a cost-effective method to heat water and other fluids by injecting steam directly into the fluid. The direct injection heater is designed to handle a wide range of flow rates and deliver hot fluids at precise temperatures.
Learn More
Flexible Metal Hose
Flexible hose prevents stress on rotary joints and unions as well as connected piping due to thermal expansion or vibration.
Learn More
Sight Flow Indicators
Kadant sight flow indicators are engineered to provide visual observation of liquid and gas flows. These pipeline indicators are available with ductile iron or bronze bodies. All glass windows are made of Pyrex® or equal.
Learn More
Thermocompressors
Kadant Johnson steam jet thermocompressors are designed to boost low pressure steam by accurately mixing the low pressure steam with high pressure steam.
Learn More
Corrugator Steam Systems
Developing an integrated corrugated steam system is key to efficiently meeting the production speeds and improving operational runnability of modern corrugators.
Learn More
Fiber Processing
Pulping & Detrashing
Complete systems for all pulping and detrashing applications based on your requirements for quality, energy efficiency, and maximum fiber recovery.
Learn More
Heat Transfer
A complete line of energy-efficient heat transfer products for the chemical pulp mill including blow-heat systems, multiple-effect evaporator & concentrator trains, indirect liquor heaters, condensate segregation, stripping, and methanol recovery.
Learn More
Recausticizing
Economic recausticizing solutions for the kraft and soda processes, including innovative upgrades to clarification, filtration, and grit management solutions - all designed to maximize efficiency, reduce energy consumption and meet environmental regulations.
Learn More
Pulp Washing
The world’s only all-in-one, multi-stage displacement pulp washer, The Kadant Chemi-Washer® is a proven performer for brown stock and bleach plant applications the world over.
Learn More
Screening
A full range of innovative options for screening stock pulp. Cost-effective solutions for a variety of applications including wastepaper recycling, deinking, virgin fiber and approach flow processing.
Learn More
Cleaning
Comprehensive cleaning solutions for high efficiency removal of all types of contaminants from pulp slurries.
Learn More
Granules
Fiber-based Granules
Kadant GranTek Inc. transforms papermaking waste products into several viable cellulose granular products used as carriers for pest control in crop protection, green space maintenance, as an all purpose industrial absorbent and as premium cat box fillers.
Learn More
Doctoring
Doctor & Roll Cleaning Blades
Doctor and roll cleaning blades are used to clean rolls and remove stock accumulations, water, pitch, and filler buildup.
Learn More
Doctor & Roll Cleaning Blade Holders
Proper doctoring or roll cleaning is critical to many industrial processes and goes beyond choosing a doctor or roll cleaning blade.
Learn More
Roll Cleaner Assemblies
Roll cleaner assemblies are comprised of a roll cleaning blade, blade holder, structural beam, brackets and bearings along with an option to oscillate.
Learn More
Double Doctoring Systems
A double doctor system provides the extra performance of two independently adjustable doctor blades within one unit.
Learn More
Cleaning
M-clean™ System
The M-clean system is a modular cleaning system for fabrics, belts, and rolls in process industries.
Learn More
Press Section Felt Cleaning Assembly
Among other applications, the press section felt cleaning assembly, also known as UHLE pipe, is designed to enhance uniform CD dewatering and cleaning, and minimize energy consumption on the press section of a paper machine.
Learn More
Spray Nozzles
Spray nozzles are used to remove contaminants and are essential in the cleaning process of many manufacturing processes.
Learn More
Stationary and Oscillating Showers
Shower systems are used to clean contaminates off machine fabric. Stationary and oscillating shower systems are available for a variety of applications.
Learn More
Mist Elimination Systems
The Mist Eliminator incorporates standard paper machine components to thoroughly clean forming fabrics and eliminate mist that is often associated with high-pressure showering.
Learn More
Electro-Mechanical Shower Oscillators
Electro-mechanical shower oscillators are precisely synchronized with the machine speed and fabric loop to ensure that 100% of the fabric is cleaned.
Learn More
Filtration
Inline Pressure Filters
In-line filters can have
a single or duplex arrangement. A single in-line filter is used in applications where the flow can be interrupted, or the filter can be bypassed when the filter element is serviced. Duo filters are used when continuous filtration is required.
Learn More
Water Resource Recovery Strainers
A proper water resource recovery system is used to effectively and efficiently reclaim white water, heat, chemicals, and fiber from a variety of paper and pulp mill applications, including DAF filtrate, save-all water, and seal pit water.
Learn More
Forming
High-Resolution™ Forming System
The High-Resolution forming system is designed for use with packaging grades of paper. This three-component system consisting of high-resolution drainage structures, Stepfoil™ technology, and high precision vacuum control provides the papermaker with excellent activity control across broad grade structures and different furnishes while maintaining an open sheet.
Learn More
Rotary Joints & Unions
Rotary Joints & Rotary Unions
A rotary joint, also referred to as a rotary union or rotating union, permits the flow of various media from a stationary supply pipe and into and/or out of rotating equipment. Heat transfer and hydraulic media typically used with rotary joints and rotating unions include steam, water, thermal oil, hydraulic oil, air, and coolant.
Learn More
Custom Rotary Unions & Swivels
Kadant Johnson’s product innovation team focuses on making the best solution in the shortest time possible. We provide rapid design and manufacturing services to ensure our new project solutions process for custom rotary unions and swivel joints put our customers at the center of our schedule.
Learn More
Multi-Passage Rotary Unions
Multi-passage (MP) rotary unions are used when more than one media are used simultaneously. An MP rotary union provides multiple seals between stationary connections and rotating equipment, such as a drum, index table, clutch, or spindle.
Learn More
Expansion Joints & Flexible Connectors
Rubber Expansion Joints
Hand-crafted rubber expansion joints available in single- and multiple-arch designs are custom-built to fit your application requirements. Options include PTFE-lined, concentric reducing, eccentric reducing, filled arch, lightweight, and off-set configurations.
Learn More
Metal Bellows Expansion Joints
Custom-engineered single- and dual-bellows designs made from 18-8 stainless steel alloy 321 with high intergranular corrosion resistance. Options include PTFE-lined, universally-tied, pressure-balanced, Gimbal, and hinged, among other configurations.
Learn More
PTFE Expansion Joints
Solid-molded PTFE expansion joints are corrosion-resistant and made to withstand the high pressure and temperature in a compact, space-saving design. Available in standard sizes 1” to 12” with two, three, or five convolutions.
Learn More
Fabric Expansion Joints
Non-metallic, flue-duct expansion joints available in eight standard profiles to fit your application requirements up to 2,000 F. Custom-designed with single-layer and composite belts and elastomers with excellent abrasion resistance.
Learn More
Flexible Metal Hose & Connectors
Corrugated metal hose with and without external braiding and metal pump connectors to absorb vibration, misalignment, and piping thermal expansion or contraction. Options include rubber covering, unique alloys, and sizes from 0.25” to 12”.
Learn More
Industrial Hose
Custom-engineered and hand-built flexible hose for a variety of industrial applications including high-pressure FDA compliant sanitary hose, chemical hose, air hose, petroleum hose, and material handling hose. Lengths available up to 500 feet and diameters up to 28”.
Learn More
Jet Devices
Desuperheaters
Desuperheaters reduce the temperature of superheated steam to its saturation point for optimal heat transfer and efficiency.
Learn More
Direct Steam Injection Heaters
A direct steam injection heater provides a cost-effective method to heat water and other fluids by injecting steam directly into the fluid. The direct injection heater is designed to handle a wide range of flow rates and deliver hot fluids at precise temperatures.
Learn More
Thermocompressors
Kadant Johnson steam jet thermocompressors are designed to boost low pressure steam by accurately mixing the low pressure steam with high pressure steam.
Learn More
Condensate Pumps
Condensate Pumps
With no maintenance-intensive components to leak, wear, or fail, the Liqui-Mover condensate pump is a naturally more reliable than conventional pumps. As a result, the Liqui-Mover condensate pump will work longer, with less maintenance and far less downtime than conventional pumps.
Learn More
Replacement Level Control
Replacement level controls are reliable and cost-effective control assemblies for servicing pressure powered pumps and pumping traps.
Learn More
Steam Systems
Corrugator Steam Systems
Developing an integrated corrugated steam system is key to efficiently meeting the production speeds and improving operational runnability of modern corrugators.
Learn More
Steam Systems
Kadant Johnson combines over 80 years of process expertise and an extensive product portfolio to deliver cost-effective, application-specific solutions.
Learn More
Accessories
Flexible Metal Hose
Flexible hose prevents stress on rotary joints and unions as well as connected piping due to thermal expansion or vibration.
Learn More
Sight Flow Indicators
Kadant sight flow indicators are engineered to provide visual observation of liquid and gas flows. These pipeline indicators are available with ductile iron or bronze bodies. All glass windows are made of Pyrex® or equal.
Learn More
Vacuum Breakers
Kadant Johnson vacuum breakers provide a simple, dependable way to relieve unwanted vacuum which may develop in a closed vessel or pipeline. They can be used to prevent contamination from back siphonage in fluid handling systems, and to protect equipment against collapse or implosion.
Learn More
Air & Steam Separators
To improve the operating efficiency of pneumatic equipment, Kadant Johnson air separators eliminate 99% of entrained contaminants including moisture, pipe scale, dirt and oil.
Learn More
OCC, Recycled Stock & Pulp Preparation
Pulping & Detrashing
Complete systems for all pulping and detrashing applications based on your requirements for quality, energy efficiency, and maximum fiber recovery.
Learn More
Screening
A full range of innovative options for screening stock pulp. Cost-effective solutions for a variety of applications including wastepaper recycling, deinking, virgin fiber and approach flow processing.
Learn More
Cleaning
Comprehensive cleaning solutions for high efficiency removal of all types of contaminants from pulp slurries.
Learn More
Thickening
Recovery systems for white water, heat, chemicals, and fiber for a variety of paper and pulp mill applications.
Learn More
Deinking
Based on our advanced flotation technology, the MAK-C Deinking Cell offers maximum yield and efficiency.
Learn More
High Shear Devices
Top-performing refiners and dispersers built tough and used across the globe.
Learn More
Chemical Pulp Systems
Heat Transfer
A complete line of energy-efficient heat transfer products for the chemical pulp mill including blow-heat systems, multiple-effect evaporator & concentrator trains, indirect liquor heaters, condensate segregation, stripping, and methanol recovery.
Learn More
Recausticizing
Economic recausticizing solutions for the kraft and soda processes, including innovative upgrades to clarification, filtration, and grit management solutions - all designed to maximize efficiency, reduce energy consumption and meet environmental regulations.
Learn More
Pulp Washing
The world’s only all-in-one, multi-stage displacement pulp washer, The Kadant Chemi-Washer® is a proven performer for brown stock and bleach plant applications the world over.
Learn More
Screening
A full range of innovative options for screening stock pulp. Cost-effective solutions for a variety of applications including wastepaper recycling, deinking, virgin fiber and approach flow processing.
Learn More
Cleaning
Comprehensive cleaning solutions for high efficiency removal of all types of contaminants from pulp slurries.
Learn More
Thickening
Recovery systems for white water, heat, chemicals, and fiber for a variety of paper and pulp mill applications.
Learn More
Approach Flow Systems
Screening
A full range of innovative options for screening stock pulp. Cost-effective solutions for a variety of applications including wastepaper recycling, deinking, virgin fiber and approach flow processing.
Learn More
Cleaning
Comprehensive cleaning solutions for high efficiency removal of all types of contaminants from pulp slurries.
Learn More
Thickening
Recovery systems for white water, heat, chemicals, and fiber for a variety of paper and pulp mill applications.
Learn More
Investors
News
Careers
Blog
English
Chinese
French
In-line filters can have
a single or duplex arrangement. A single in-line filter is used in applications where the flow can be interrupted, or the filter can be bypassed when the filter element is serviced. Duo filters are used when continuous filtration is required.
Learn More
M-clean™ System
The M-clean system is a modular cleaning system for fabrics, belts, and rolls in process industries.
Learn More
Press Section Felt Cleaning Assembly
Among other applications, the press section felt cleaning assembly, also known as UHLE pipe, is designed to enhance uniform CD dewatering and cleaning, and minimize energy consumption on the press section of a paper machine.
Learn More
Doctor & Roll Cleaning Blades
Doctor and roll cleaning blades are used to clean rolls and remove stock accumulations, water, pitch, and filler buildup.
Learn More
Doctor & Roll Cleaning Blade Holders
Proper doctoring or roll cleaning is critical to many industrial processes and goes beyond choosing a doctor or roll cleaning blade.
Learn More
Roll Cleaner Assemblies
Roll cleaner assemblies are comprised of a roll cleaning blade, blade holder, structural beam, brackets and bearings along with an option to oscillate.
Learn More
Desuperheaters
Desuperheaters reduce the temperature of superheated steam to its saturation point for optimal heat transfer and efficiency.
Learn More
Direct Steam Injection Heaters
A direct steam injection heater provides a cost-effective method to heat water and other fluids by injecting steam directly into the fluid. The direct injection heater is designed to handle a wide range of flow rates and deliver hot fluids at precise temperatures.
Learn More
Flexible Metal Hose
Flexible hose prevents stress on rotary joints and unions as well as connected piping due to thermal expansion or vibration.
Learn More
Sight Flow Indicators
Kadant sight flow indicators are engineered to provide visual observation of liquid and gas flows. These pipeline indicators are available with ductile iron or bronze bodies. All glass windows are made of Pyrex® or equal.
Learn More
Thermocompressors
Kadant Johnson steam jet thermocompressors are designed to boost low pressure steam by accurately mixing the low pressure steam with high pressure steam.
Learn More
Corrugator Steam Systems
Developing an integrated corrugated steam system is key to efficiently meeting the production speeds and improving operational runnability of modern corrugators.
Learn More
Pulping & Detrashing
Complete systems for all pulping and detrashing applications based on your requirements for quality, energy efficiency, and maximum fiber recovery.
Learn More
Heat Transfer
A complete line of energy-efficient heat transfer products for the chemical pulp mill including blow-heat systems, multiple-effect evaporator & concentrator trains, indirect liquor heaters, condensate segregation, stripping, and methanol recovery.
Learn More
Recausticizing
Economic recausticizing solutions for the kraft and soda processes, including innovative upgrades to clarification, filtration, and grit management solutions - all designed to maximize efficiency, reduce energy consumption and meet environmental regulations.
Learn More
Pulp Washing
The world’s only all-in-one, multi-stage displacement pulp washer, The Kadant Chemi-Washer® is a proven performer for brown stock and bleach plant applications the world over.
Learn More
Screening
A full range of innovative options for screening stock pulp. Cost-effective solutions for a variety of applications including wastepaper recycling, deinking, virgin fiber and approach flow processing.
Learn More
Cleaning
Comprehensive cleaning solutions for high efficiency removal of all types of contaminants from pulp slurries.
Learn More
Fiber-based Granules
Kadant GranTek Inc. transforms papermaking waste products into several viable cellulose granular products used as carriers for pest control in crop protection, green space maintenance, as an all purpose industrial absorbent and as premium cat box fillers.
Learn More
Doctor & Roll Cleaning Blades
Doctor and roll cleaning blades are used to clean rolls and remove stock accumulations, water, pitch, and filler buildup.
Learn More
Doctor & Roll Cleaning Blade Holders
Proper doctoring or roll cleaning is critical to many industrial processes and goes beyond choosing a doctor or roll cleaning blade.
Learn More
Roll Cleaner Assemblies
Roll cleaner assemblies are comprised of a roll cleaning blade, blade holder, structural beam, brackets and bearings along with an option to oscillate.
Learn More
Double Doctoring Systems
A double doctor system provides the extra performance of two independently adjustable doctor blades within one unit.
Learn More
M-clean™ System
The M-clean system is a modular cleaning system for fabrics, belts, and rolls in process industries.
Learn More
Press Section Felt Cleaning Assembly
Among other applications, the press section felt cleaning assembly, also known as UHLE pipe, is designed to enhance uniform CD dewatering and cleaning, and minimize energy consumption on the press section of a paper machine.
Learn More
Spray Nozzles
Spray nozzles are used to remove contaminants and are essential in the cleaning process of many manufacturing processes.
Learn More
Stationary and Oscillating Showers
Shower systems are used to clean contaminates off machine fabric. Stationary and oscillating shower systems are available for a variety of applications.
Learn More
Mist Elimination Systems
The Mist Eliminator incorporates standard paper machine components to thoroughly clean forming fabrics and eliminate mist that is often associated with high-pressure showering.
Learn More
Electro-Mechanical Shower Oscillators
Electro-mechanical shower oscillators are precisely synchronized with the machine speed and fabric loop to ensure that 100% of the fabric is cleaned.
Learn More
Inline Pressure Filters
In-line filters can have
a single or duplex arrangement. A single in-line filter is used in applications where the flow can be interrupted, or the filter can be bypassed when the filter element is serviced. Duo filters are used when continuous filtration is required.
Learn More
Water Resource Recovery Strainers
A proper water resource recovery system is used to effectively and efficiently reclaim white water, heat, chemicals, and fiber from a variety of paper and pulp mill applications, including DAF filtrate, save-all water, and seal pit water.
Learn More
High-Resolution™ Forming System
The High-Resolution forming system is designed for use with packaging grades of paper. This three-component system consisting of high-resolution drainage structures, Stepfoil™ technology, and high precision vacuum control provides the papermaker with excellent activity control across broad grade structures and different furnishes while maintaining an open sheet.
Learn More
Rotary Joints & Rotary Unions
A rotary joint, also referred to as a rotary union or rotating union, permits the flow of various media from a stationary supply pipe and into and/or out of rotating equipment. Heat transfer and hydraulic media typically used with rotary joints and rotating unions include steam, water, thermal oil, hydraulic oil, air, and coolant.
Learn More
Custom Rotary Unions & Swivels
Kadant Johnson’s product innovation team focuses on making the best solution in the shortest time possible. We provide rapid design and manufacturing services to ensure our new project solutions process for custom rotary unions and swivel joints put our customers at the center of our schedule.
Learn More
Multi-Passage Rotary Unions
Multi-passage (MP) rotary unions are used when more than one media are used simultaneously. An MP rotary union provides multiple seals between stationary connections and rotating equipment, such as a drum, index table, clutch, or spindle.
Learn More
Rubber Expansion Joints
Hand-crafted rubber expansion joints available in single- and multiple-arch designs are custom-built to fit your application requirements. Options include PTFE-lined, concentric reducing, eccentric reducing, filled arch, lightweight, and off-set configurations.
Learn More
Metal Bellows Expansion Joints
Custom-engineered single- and dual-bellows designs made from 18-8 stainless steel alloy 321 with high intergranular corrosion resistance. Options include PTFE-lined, universally-tied, pressure-balanced, Gimbal, and hinged, among other configurations.
Learn More
PTFE Expansion Joints
Solid-molded PTFE expansion joints are corrosion-resistant and made to withstand the high pressure and temperature in a compact, space-saving design. Available in standard sizes 1” to 12” with two, three, or five convolutions.
Learn More
Fabric Expansion Joints
Non-metallic, flue-duct expansion joints available in eight standard profiles to fit your application requirements up to 2,000 F. Custom-designed with single-layer and composite belts and elastomers with excellent abrasion resistance.
Learn More
Flexible Metal Hose & Connectors
Corrugated metal hose with and without external braiding and metal pump connectors to absorb vibration, misalignment, and piping thermal expansion or contraction. Options include rubber covering, unique alloys, and sizes from 0.25” to 12”.
Learn More
Industrial Hose
Custom-engineered and hand-built flexible hose for a variety of industrial applications including high-pressure FDA compliant sanitary hose, chemical hose, air hose, petroleum hose, and material handling hose. Lengths available up to 500 feet and diameters up to 28”.
Learn More
Desuperheaters
Desuperheaters reduce the temperature of superheated steam to its saturation point for optimal heat transfer and efficiency.
Learn More
Direct Steam Injection Heaters
A direct steam injection heater provides a cost-effective method to heat water and other fluids by injecting steam directly into the fluid. The direct injection heater is designed to handle a wide range of flow rates and deliver hot fluids at precise temperatures.
Learn More
Thermocompressors
Kadant Johnson steam jet thermocompressors are designed to boost low pressure steam by accurately mixing the low pressure steam with high pressure steam.
Learn More
Condensate Pumps
With no maintenance-intensive components to leak, wear, or fail, the Liqui-Mover condensate pump is a naturally more reliable than conventional pumps. As a result, the Liqui-Mover condensate pump will work longer, with less maintenance and far less downtime than conventional pumps.
Learn More
Replacement Level Control
Replacement level controls are reliable and cost-effective control assemblies for servicing pressure powered pumps and pumping traps.
Learn More
Corrugator Steam Systems
Developing an integrated corrugated steam system is key to efficiently meeting the production speeds and improving operational runnability of modern corrugators.
Learn More
Steam Systems
Kadant Johnson combines over 80 years of process expertise and an extensive product portfolio to deliver cost-effective, application-specific solutions.
Learn More
Flexible Metal Hose
Flexible hose prevents stress on rotary joints and unions as well as connected piping due to thermal expansion or vibration.
Learn More
Sight Flow Indicators
Kadant sight flow indicators are engineered to provide visual observation of liquid and gas flows. These pipeline indicators are available with ductile iron or bronze bodies. All glass windows are made of Pyrex® or equal.
Learn More
Vacuum Breakers
Kadant Johnson vacuum breakers provide a simple, dependable way to relieve unwanted vacuum which may develop in a closed vessel or pipeline. They can be used to prevent contamination from back siphonage in fluid handling systems, and to protect equipment against collapse or implosion.
Learn More
Air & Steam Separators
To improve the operating efficiency of pneumatic equipment, Kadant Johnson air separators eliminate 99% of entrained contaminants including moisture, pipe scale, dirt and oil.
Learn More
Pulping & Detrashing
Complete systems for all pulping and detrashing applications based on your requirements for quality, energy efficiency, and maximum fiber recovery.
Learn More
Screening
A full range of innovative options for screening stock pulp. Cost-effective solutions for a variety of applications including wastepaper recycling, deinking, virgin fiber and approach flow processing.
Learn More
Cleaning
Comprehensive cleaning solutions for high efficiency removal of all types of contaminants from pulp slurries.
Learn More
Thickening
Recovery systems for white water, heat, chemicals, and fiber for a variety of paper and pulp mill applications.
Learn More
Deinking
Based on our advanced flotation technology, the MAK-C Deinking Cell offers maximum yield and efficiency.
Learn More
High Shear Devices
Top-performing refiners and dispersers built tough and used across the globe.
Learn More
Heat Transfer
A complete line of energy-efficient heat transfer products for the chemical pulp mill including blow-heat systems, multiple-effect evaporator & concentrator trains, indirect liquor heaters, condensate segregation, stripping, and methanol recovery.
Learn More
Recausticizing
Economic recausticizing solutions for the kraft and soda processes, including innovative upgrades to clarification, filtration, and grit management solutions - all designed to maximize efficiency, reduce energy consumption and meet environmental regulations.
Learn More
Pulp Washing
The world’s only all-in-one, multi-stage displacement pulp washer, The Kadant Chemi-Washer® is a proven performer for brown stock and bleach plant applications the world over.
Learn More
Screening
A full range of innovative options for screening stock pulp. Cost-effective solutions for a variety of applications including wastepaper recycling, deinking, virgin fiber and approach flow processing.
Learn More
Cleaning
Comprehensive cleaning solutions for high efficiency removal of all types of contaminants from pulp slurries.
Learn More
Thickening
Recovery systems for white water, heat, chemicals, and fiber for a variety of paper and pulp mill applications.
Learn More
Screening
A full range of innovative options for screening stock pulp. Cost-effective solutions for a variety of applications including wastepaper recycling, deinking, virgin fiber and approach flow processing.
Learn More
Cleaning
Comprehensive cleaning solutions for high efficiency removal of all types of contaminants from pulp slurries.
Learn More
Thickening
Recovery systems for white water, heat, chemicals, and fiber for a variety of paper and pulp mill applications.
Learn More
Home
Privacy Statement
Privacy Policy
Effective: May 25, 2018
At Kadant, we take your privacy seriously. This Privacy Policy is meant to help you understand what information we may collect, why we collect it, what we do with it, and how you can update and manage your information. When we refer to Kadant, "we", "us", or "our", we mean our entire Company, including our divisions, subsidiaries, and affiliates.
Kadant Inc. (NYSE: KAI) is registered in the U.S. as a corporation in the State of Delaware and has its registered office at One Technology Park Drive, Westford, Massachusetts 01886. For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, the controller of personal data is Kadant and our contact details can be found in the contact section below.
The information you provide to us, or which we collect, via our websites, email notifications, mobile applications, social media applications, written correspondence (including e-mail), or through any of our offices globally, is used for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy.
INFORMATION WE COLLECT
We collect information to provide better products and services to you and to comply with our legal obligations.
Through your use of our websites, we may collect personal and non-personal information from you, including:
Your name, email address, telephone number, or similar information (“Contact Information”);
Your credit card number, billing address, shipping address, security code, and other payment transaction and verification details (“Payment Information”);
Pages and products viewed, items added to your shopping cart, ads you clicked on, emails from us you opened, browser type, operating system, IP address, and device information (“Analytical Information”);
Your mobile OS, a mobile device identifier embedded by us, or other commonly used mobile device identifiers.
We may collect your personal information or usage data from third-parties, including:
Your email address and other collected personal information about you may be forwarded to Kadant by a third-party website when you request for Kadant to contact you through a third-party website;
Your personal information may be forwarded to Kadant when you participate in a third-party application or feature, such as one of our social media pages or a similar application or feature on a third-party website;
Additional personal information may be forwarded to Kadant from third-parties to combine with the personal information we collect through your use of our websites to enhance our ability to serve you, to focus content we provide to you, and to offer you opportunities to purchase products or services we believe may interest you.
We will apply the terms of our Privacy Policy to any personal information received from a third-party, unless we have disclosed to you otherwise. Kadant is not responsible for these third-parties' dissemination of your personal information.
If you are a resident of a country in the European Economic Area (“EEA”), the personal information we collect from you may be transferred to and stored at a destination outside the EEA. The personal information may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA that work for us or one of our or third-party service providers. By submitting your personal information, you agree to this transfer, storing, and processing. We take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
We will retain your information for as long as your information is needed to provide you products or services, as required to fulfill our legal obligations, or until you tell us to delete your personal information. If you wish to delete your account or request we no longer use your information to provide you services, contact us at privacy@kadant.com.
HOW WE USE INFORMATION WE COLLECT
The information we collect will only be used in connection with your business relationship with us and to comply with legal obligations. We use your information to assist you as our customer, to provide you with the information you have requested, to improve our products, to market our products, and note your preferences to provide the best user experience possible.
We use your information for these legitimate business purposes:
Purchases: We may use your Contact Information and Payment Information to allow us to process and fulfill purchases you make.
Customer Service: We may use your Contact Information to respond to your questions about products and services and to communicate with you about relevant products or services.
Analytics: When you use our websites, we automatically collect and use Analytical Information, described above, for us to continually improve your experience with our websites and to target marketing communications and advertising to you.
Marketing: We may use your personal information to determine what products may interest you, provide you with marketing communications (unless you have opted out of such communications), and to conduct marketing research. If you contact us via our applications, you may be added to our marketing list. You may unsubscribe at any time.
INFORMATION WE SHARE
We share your information with our subsidiaries, divisions, and affiliates to inform you about products and services that may interest you. We also provide personal information to our affiliates, trusted business partners, and third-party service providers to process it for us based on our instructions and in compliance with our Privacy Policy and any other confidentiality and security measures. This includes instructions relating to processing payments, delivering packages, analyzing website or mobile application usage data, electronic and postal mail service, marketing services, social media services, and calculating, managing, and reporting sales tax.
If any personal information is provided to third-parties outside the EEA or who will access the information from outside the EEA, we will ensure approved safeguards are in place, such as the approved standard contractual clauses or the EU-US Privacy Shield. Examples of where these safeguards are in place include where we provide your information to our subsidiaries and divisions for our legitimate business purposes or to our trusted third-parties who provide the types of services mentioned above. All our subsidiaries and divisions sign standard contractual clauses approved by the European Commission to safeguard the personal information transferred across our businesses to and from the EEA.
We will disclose your personal information if required by law, regulation, or as part of a legal process. If we receive a request from a regulatory body or law enforcement agency, and if permitted under GDPR and other laws, we may disclose certain personal information to such bodies or agencies.
If Kadant is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of assets, we will continue to ensure the confidentiality of your personal information and may share or transfer your personal information to the new owners of the business or company or their advisors.
INFORMATION SECURITY
We work hard to protect Kadant and our users from unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure, or destruction of information we hold. In particular:
We use encryption to keep your data private while in transit.
We review our information collection, storage, and processing practices, including physical security measures, to prevent unauthorized access to our systems.
We restrict access to personal information to Kadant employees, contractors, and agents who need to know that information to process it for us, and who are subject to strict contractual confidentiality obligations and may be disciplined or terminated if they fail to meet these obligations.
While no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, we strive to protect the information submitted to us. We consider the sensitivity of the personal information we collect, process, and store and use the appropriate technology to protect your personal information. We cannot, however, guarantee its absolute security.
YOUR PRIVACY RIGHTS
Individuals in certain countries, including the EEA, have certain rights in relation to their personal data. For example, you have the right to request access to your personal information, the right to have a machine-readable copy of your data, the right to correct or update your personal information, and the right to have all your personal information deleted. You also have the right to object to our processing activities, as summarized below.
If you have any questions or wish to exercise your rights as described above, you may contact us at privacy@kadant.com.
COMPLIANCE AND COOPERATION WITH REGULATORS
We regularly review this Privacy Policy and make sure that we process your information in ways that comply with it.
Data transfers
We use servers around the world and your information may be processed on servers located outside of the country where you live. Regardless of where your information is processed, we apply the same protections described in this Privacy Policy. We also comply with certain legal frameworks relating to transferring data.
European requirements
If GDPR applies to the processing of your information, we provide the controls described in this Privacy Policy so you can exercise your right to request access to, update, remove, and restrict the processing of your information. You may also object to the processing of your information at any time for marketing purposes or where we rely on our legitimate interests.
We process your information for the purposes described in this policy, based on these legal grounds:
With your consent. We ask for your agreement to process your information for specific purposes and you may withdraw your consent at any time.
When pursuing legitimate interests. We process your information for our legitimate interests while applying safeguards that protect your privacy. This means we process your information for things like:
Providing, maintaining, and improving our websites to meet the needs of our users
Developing new products and features
Understanding how people use our websites to improve the performance of our websites
Marketing to inform users about our products
Detecting, preventing, or otherwise addressing fraud, abuse, security, or technical issues with our websites and
Protecting against harm to the rights, property, or safety of Kadant, our users, or the public as required or permitted by law.
When entering into or performing a contract. We process your data to provide a product or service you have asked for under a contract or when you have asked us to sign a contract.
When complying with legal obligations. We will process your data when we have a legal obligation to do so, for example, if we are responding to legal process or an enforceable governmental request.
If you have questions about our legal basis for processing information, you may contact us at privacy@kadant.com. You can contact your local data protection authority if you have concerns regarding your rights under local law or would like to file a complaint.
LINKS TO THIRD-PARTY WEBSITES
Our websites contain links to social networking and other websites and mobile applications operated and controlled by third-parties. Unless otherwise stated, any personal information you provide to any third-party website will be collected by that party and not by us and will be subject to that party’s privacy policy rather than this Privacy Policy.
COOKIES
We use “cookies” and other similar technologies (e.g., internet tag technologies, web beacons, and embedded scripts) to help provide you with a better, more personalized user experience. A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. We use these technologies to help us understand and improve how visitors use our websites, including which pages and products are viewed most frequently.
Our websites may include web beacons and cookies from third-party service providers. In some cases, that is because we have hired the third-party to provide services on our behalf, such as site analytics. Because your browser connects to those third parties' web servers to retrieve that content, those third parties can set or read their own cookies on your device and may collect information about your online activities across websites or online services.
You have a variety of tools to control cookies, web beacons and similar technologies, including browser controls to block and delete cookies and controls from some third-party analytics service providers to opt out of data collection through web beacons and similar technologies.
Most web browsers automatically accept cookies but provide controls that allow you to block or delete them. For example, in Google Chrome, you can block or delete cookies by clicking Settings > Show advanced settings > Content settings > Cookies. In Microsoft Edge, you can block or delete cookies by clicking Settings > Privacy > Cookies. Instructions for blocking or deleting cookies in other browsers may be available in each browser's privacy or help documentation.
Please note that if you choose to block cookies, you may not be able to use certain site features and preferences that are dependent on cookies may be lost. If you choose to delete cookies, settings and preferences controlled by those cookies will be deleted and may need to be recreated.
CHILDREN
We do not intend to solicit or collect personal information from anyone under the age of 18. If you are under the age of 18, do not enter information into this site or engage in our services.
CONTACTING US
If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, please write to us by mail at Kadant Inc., Attn: Website Inquiries, One Technology Park Drive, Westford, MA 01886 USA, or email us at privacy@kadant.com.
CHANGES
We may update this Privacy Policy occasionally. Please check the “Effective Date” at the top of this page to see when this Privacy Policy was last revised. Unless otherwise noted, any changes we make to this Privacy Policy will become effective immediately once posted on this page. Your continued use of our websites following any changes to this Privacy Policy indicates your consent to the practices described in the revised Privacy Policy. Unless stated otherwise, our Privacy Policy applies to all information we have about you and your account.
Contact Us
Popular Links
Process Optimization Tips
Media Library
Custom Rotary Unions
Blodac Granular Carrier
Gran-sorb Industrial Absorbent
About Kadant
Quick Facts
Research & Development
Manufacturing Locations
Privacy
Terms Of Use
© 2020 Kadant Inc. or its affiliates. All rights reserved.
You are leaving Kadant.com
You are leaving the Kadant web site and will be redirected to another site. Kadant makes no endorsement or claims about the accuracy or content of the information contained in these sites. The security and privacy policies on these sites may be different than Kadant.
Continue
Close Window
?
